ERICA INGRAM

evoingram@aquoco.onmicrosoft.com

- (206) 478-5028
- Seattle, Washington
- in aquocotrans
- evoingram
- www.ericaingram.com

Business professional with a knack for solving real-world problems and overcoming challenges, extremely resourceful and adaptable with excellent communication skills from a decade-long writing career and another decade in court transcription; thorough, self-disciplined, and well equipped to work independently under regular strict deadlines.

Skills

TECH SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Visual Basic

Git

MySQL

React

Redux

GSAP

Microsoft Access

Adobe XD

LESS

Bootstrap

Emmet

Jest

Formik

SASS

jQuery

Python

PHP

API UI

REST

JSON

LEGAL SERVICES SKILLS

Legal Research
Editing
Writing
Transcription
Litigation Support
Proofreading
Project Management

Employment

Lambda School, Team Lead, Remote

Jan. 2020 to Present

- Code review for every student in my team twice per week
- Hosted two stand-up meetings with six students weekly
- Presentations on various resources to facilitate students' growth during stand-ups
- Mentored & provided feedback to students on improvement areas
- Tracked attendance and other student metrics
- Use of Slackbot & Slack Workflow Builder to manage tasks, information, and reminders

A Quo Co., Owner/Operator, Seattle, WA

May 2009 to Present

- Diverse customer base, serving attorneys and pro se parties
- Used text-analyzing software on over 10,000 transcript pages to produce autocorrect entries in Word to improve typing speed/accuracy and automated creation of those entries
- Unique features such as authority hyperlinking via CourtListener, .gov sites as well as tables of authority via VBA automation
- Consistently produced twice the number of transcript pages as most of my colleagues due to VBA automation

Projects

Prisoner Skills App Deployed Project

Feb. 2020 to Feb. 2020 Code on GitHub

 React and Redux app to help match prisoners with specific skills to potential employers

NASA Random APOD Generator Deployed Project

Jan. 2020 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

 React and Redux app integrating the NASA Astronomy Photo of the Day API through a generated random date on button click

Transcription Management Deployed Offline

June 2017 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

- Developed using Visual Basic for Applications, MS Access, and MySQL
- Transcript production workflow management
- Integrated with Office, Acrobat, and WinSCP libraries and several APIs such as CourtListener, Wunderlist, PayPal, OneNote, and others

Company Website Deployed Project

June 2017 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

- Made with LESS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Ranks in 90th percentile in Google PageSpeed Insights and first page results for "seattle transcription" in Google, page two for Bing/Duckduckgo

Multi-Page Marketing Website Deployed Project

June 2017 to Jan. 2020 Code on GitHub

Developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SVG, and LESS

Education

Lambda School, Remote

Oct. 2019 to Present

Full Stack Web Development and Computer Science

Nine-month computer science and software engineering academy providing intense immersive curriculum in web development and computer science-focused topics such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, React, Redux, Python, Express, Git, SQL, Bootstrap, NPM/Yarn, GSAP, & Jest